Charles Ives Rare and Non-Commercial Sound Recordings
Yale University Music Library
- Instantaneous discs, Series V; All discs in this series are 12 inch lacquer discs, except where noted.
  - Ives Songs, Disc 1, 1970 September 9; 1 (Box 109, Item barcode 39002038373420)
  - The London Recordings, undated; 1 (Box 108, Item barcode 39002038372026)
  - Concord Piano Sonata, 2nd Movement; Part 9 and 10, 1939 September 28; 1 (Box 109, Item barcode 39002038372042)
  - Concord Piano Sonata, 1st Movement; Part 7 and 8, 1939 September 28; 1 (Box 109, Item barcode 39002038372059)
  - Concord Piano Sonata, 1st Movement; Part 5 and 6, 1939 September 28; 1 (Box 109, Item barcode 39002038372067)
  - Concord Piano Sonata, 3rd and 4th Movements; Part 11 and 12, 1939 September 28; 1 (Box 109, Item barcode 39002038372034)
  - Sonata for Violin and Piano, 1st Movement; Part 1, 1946 February 22; 1 (Box 109, Item barcode 39002038372083)
    Performers: Joan Field, violin; Ray Lev, Piano.
    WNYC.
  - Sonata for Violin and Piano, 3rd Movement; Part 1, 1946 February 22; 1 (Box 109, Item barcode 39002038374154)
  - Sonata for Violin and Piano, 3rd Movement; Part 2, 1946 February 22; 1 (Box 109, Item barcode 39002038372075)
  - Symphony No. 4, 1st Movement, Prelude and Fugue, undated; 1 (Box 109, Item barcode 39002038372596)
  - Symphony No. 4, 2nd Movement, Fugue, undated; 1; Unlike all other materials in this collection, this item is not digitized. The disc has a large crack and is deformed and therefore could not be digitized. (Box 109, Item barcode 39002038372604)
  - Introduction Script for after 4th Symphony -- 1st String Quartet, undated; 1 (Box 109, Item barcode 39002038372612)
  - 1st String Quartet, Movements I and II (arr. for orchestra by Hermann), undated; 1 (Box 109, Item barcode 39002038372620)
  - Symphony No. 4, 1st Movement, Prelude and Fugue -- 1st String Quartet, Movements I and II (arr. for orchestra by Hermann), 1943 March 16; 1 (Box 109, Item barcode 39002038372638)
    Columbia test pressing.
  - Symphony No. 4, Fugue -- 1st String Quartet, II from cello to end, 1943 March 16; 1 (Box 109, Item barcode 39002038372646)
  - Barn Dance -- Goodnight Ladies -- Serenity; part 3 and 7, 1943 March 31; 1 (Box 109, Item barcode 39002038372653)
    ARS.
  - Danbury Fair March -- Largo for Strings; part 1 and 5, 1943 March 31; 1 (Box 109, Item barcode 39002038372661)
  - Concord Piano Sonata, 4th Movement; Part 13, 1939 September 28; 1 (Box 109, Item barcode 39002128474476)
  - Sonata No. 3 for Piano and Violin, Third Movement, Adagio Cantabile; Parts 5 and 6, undated; 1 (Box 109, Item barcode 39002128474484)
  - Sonata No 3 for Piano and Violin, First Movement Cont., Adagio Cantabile; Part 2, undated; 1 (Box 109, Item barcode 39002128474492)
  - American Music Festival; Part 6, 1940 February 12; 1 (Box 109, Item barcode 39002128474500)
    American Music Festival. WNYC, 4pm.
  - Ives: Hawthorne, Part 2 -- ANON (Fr. XIIIS.) La Septime Estampie Royale -- Ives: Thoreau, Last Part, 1939 January 20; 1 (Box 109, Item barcode 39002128474518)
  - Symphony No. 3, First Movement; Part 1, 1946 September 11; 1 (Box 109, Item barcode 39002128474526)
  - Concord Piano Sonata, 4th Movement; Part 13, 1939 September 28; 1 (Box 109, Item barcode 39002128474542)
  - Beethoven Op. 53, Part 5 Side 5 -- Ives: Thoreau, Part 3 Side 15, 1939 January 20; 1 (Box 109, Item barcode 39002128474534)
  - Beethoven Sonata Op. 53, Side 3 -- Ives: The Alcotts, Side 13, 1939 January 20; 1 (Box 109, Item barcode 39002128474559)
  - Beethoven Sonata Op.53, Side 2 -- Ives: The Alcotts, Side 12, 1939 January 20; 1 (Box 109, Item barcode 39002128474567)
  - Beethoven Sonata Op. 53, Side 4 -- Ives: Thoreau, Side 14, 1939 January 20; 1 (Box 109, Item barcode 39002128474575)
  - Sonata No. 2, Emerson, 1959 October 19; 1 (Box 109, Item barcode 39002128474583)
  - Sonata for Violin and Piano,1st Movement; Part 1, 1946 February 22; 1 (Box 109, Item barcode 39002038374162)
    Performers: Joan Field, violin; Ray Lev, piano. American Music Festival.
  - Sonata for Violin and Piano, 2nd Movement; Part 2, 1946 February 22; 1 (Box 109, Item barcode 39002038374170)
  - Sonata for Violin and Piano, 3rd Movement; Part 2, 1946 February 22; 1 (Box 109, Item barcode 39002038374188)
  - Violin Sonata No. 2, 2nd Movement, undated; 1 (Box 108, Item barcode 39002038374204)
    Performers: Jerome Goldstein, violin; Rex Tillson, piano.
  - (Indecipherable), undated; 1 (Box 108, Item barcode 39002038374196)
  - Speak-O-Phone Disc: Sound of Emerson, undated; 1; 10 inch aluminium disc (Box 109a, Item barcode 39002128475044)
  - Speak-O-Phone Disc B: [untitled], undated; 1; 7 inch aluminium disc (Box 109a, Item barcode 39002128475051)
  - Speak-O-Phone Disc A: 1st Emerson Transcription part 1, undated; 1; 7 inch aluminium disc (Box 109a, Item barcode 39002128475069)
  - Speak-O-Phone Disc: Emerson Transcription part 1 and part 2, undated; 1; 7 inch aluminium disc (Box 109a, Item barcode 39002128475077)
  - The MeloTone Recordings, undated; 1 (Box 109a, Item barcode 39002128475085)
    1.Side 3, band 2/ 2. ", band 3/ 3. Side 4, band 1/ ", band 2/ 5. ", band 3, 6. Side 5.
  - The Speak-O-Phone Recordings, undated; 1 (Box 109a, Item barcode 39002128475093)
    1. 8" disc, other side/ 2. 10" disc, label side/ 3. ", other side.
  - The Mary Howard Recordings, undated; 1 (Box 109a, Item barcode 39002128475101)
    Performer: Charles Ives (?). 1. 2nd Piano Sonata - Side 1, band 1/ 2. The same - band 2/ 3. The same - side 2/ 4. Old Quickstep March/ 5. Abolition Riots - Part 1.
  - The Melo Tone Recordings, undated; 1 (Box 109a, Item barcode 39002128475119)
    1. Side 1, band 1/ 2. ", band 2/ 3. ", band 3/ 4. ", band 4/ 5. Side 2/ 6. Side 3, band 1.
  - The Speak-O-Phone Recordings, undated; 1 (Box 109a, Item barcode 39002128475127)
    1. 7" disc A, label side/ 2. ", other side/ 3. 7" disc B, label side/ 4. 7" disc B, other side/ 5. 8" disc, label side.
  - The Mary Howard Recordings, undated; 1 (Box 109a, Item barcode 39002128475135)
    Performer: Charles Ives (?). Abolition Riots, Part 1, other side -- Abolition Riots, Part 2 -- War Song, First Time -- Second Time -- Third Time.
  - Passages from 2nd Piano Sonata, 1943 April 24; 1 (Box 109a, Item barcode 39002128475143)
    Performer: Charles Ives (?)
  - Passages from 2nd Piano Sonata (noisy (copy?)), 1943 April 24; 1 (Box 109a, Item barcode 39002128475150)
  - Abolition Riot in Boston in 50s, Part 1 (noisier (copy?)), 1943 April 24; 1 (Box 109a, Item barcode 39002128475168)
  - Abolition Riot in Boston in 50s, Part 1 (Original?), 1943 April 24; 1 (Box 109a, Item barcode 39002128475176)
  - War Song, 1st Time, 1943 April 24; 1 (Box 109a, Item barcode 39002128475184)
  - War Song, 3rd Time (Words clearest on This.), 1943 April 24; 1 (Box 109a, Item barcode 39002128475192)
  - [untitled], 1938 May 11; 1 (Box 109a, Item barcode 39002128475200)
  - Old Quickstep March (Original), 1943 April 24; 1 (Box 109a, Item barcode 39002128475218)
  - War Song, 2nd time (Best general record), 1943 April 24; 1 (Box 109a, Item barcode 39002128475226)
  - Piano - Trials (D), 1938 May 11; 1 (Box 109a, Item barcode 39002128475234)
  - [untitled] (C), 1938 May 11; 1 (Box 109a, Item barcode 39002128475242)
  - [untitled] (a), 1938 May 11; 1 (Box 109a, Item barcode 39002128475259)
  - Pianoforte Sonata, 1933 June 12; 1 (Box 109a, Item barcode 39002128475267)
  - [untitled] (4), 1938 May 11; 1 (Box 109a, Item barcode 39002128475275)
  - [untitled] (5), 1938 May 11; 1 (Box 109a, Item barcode 39002128475283)
  - Pianoforte Sonata, 1933 June 12; 1 (Box 109a, Item barcode 39002128475291)
- Open reel tapes, Series VI
  - Symphony No. 4 (world premiere), undated; 1 (Box 103, Item barcode 39002038370285)
    Performers: American Symphony Orchestra; Leopold Stokowski (conductor).
  - Charles Ives 99th Birthday Party Concert, 1973 October 19; 1 (Box 111, Item barcode 39002038373214)
  - Charles Ives Centennial Festival Conference: Sacred Songs and Organ Music by Ives, 1974 October 21; 1 (Box 112, Item barcode 39002038373263)
  - Charles Ives 99th Birthday Party Concert; Tape 2, 1973 October 19; 1 (Box 112, Item barcode 39002038373289)
  - Ives Centennial Conference; Center Church, 1974 October 21; 1 (Box 112, Item barcode 39002038373255)
  - Ives Potpourri; Dub, 1974 November 20; 1 (Box 112, Item barcode 39002038373230)
  - Ives Potpourri; Dub; Sprague, 1974 October 21–1974 November 20; 1 (Box 111, Item barcode 39002038373222)
  - Ives Potpourri; Sprague, 1974 October 21–1974 November 20; 1 (Box 112, Item barcode 39002038373248)
  - Melotone, 1938 May 11; 1 (Box 105, Item barcode 39002038373404)
  - Piano Trials; Melotone, 1934 May 15–1938 May 11; 1 (Box 105, Item barcode 39002038373313)
    Performers: The Pan American Chamber Orchestra; Nicolas Slominsky (conductor).
  - Sonata excerpts, 1943; 1 (Box 105, Item barcode 39002038373339)
  - Mary Howard; 6 tracks; reel 5; Ives piano, 1943 April 24; 1 (Box 105, Item barcode 39002038373388)
  - Mary Howard; from Mary Howard's green label disc, 1943 April 24; 1 (Box 105, Item barcode 39002038373396)
  - Mary Howard; Melotone, 1938 May 11–1943 June 24; 1 (Box 105, Item barcode 39002038373347)
  - Melotone, 1938 May 11; 1 (Box 105, Item barcode 39002038373321)
  - Speak-o-Phone transcriptions; 7" discs; 10" discs, undated; 1 (Box 105, Item barcode 39002038373354)
  - Emerson; Speak-o-Phone transcriptions, 1933 December 6; 1 (Box 105, Item barcode 39002038373362)
  - Emerson transcription; Speak-o-phone; Mary Howard, 1943 April 24; 1 (Box 105, Item barcode 39002038373370)
  - The Alcotts; Green label; lacquer copies, 1943; 1 (Box 105, Item barcode 39002038373305)
  - 3 Places in New England (live), undated; 1 (Box 105A, Item barcode 39002038373719)
  - Meadowbrook: Debussy: Cinq Poemes de Baudelaire -- Ives: The Cage -- The Children's Hour -- Charlie Rutlage; dub, 1968 July 29; 1 (Box 105A, Item barcode 39002038373727)
    Performers: Meadowbrook (?).
  - 5 songs, undated; 1 (Box 105A, Item barcode 39002038373776)
    Performers: Ward Devenny.
  - Emerson -- Sonata No. 2, 1959 October 19–1991 April 17; 1 (Box 105A, Item barcode 39002038373800)
  - Songs, 1964 April; 1 (Box 105A, Item barcode 39002038373826)
    Performers: Bauman; Barnett.
  - Charles Ives's Theater Orchestra Music, 1974 November 25; 1 (Box 105A, Item barcode 39002038373834)
    Performers: Mr. J. Sinclair.
  - Three Quarter-tone Pieces for Two Pianos; Dub, 1966 November 13; 1 (Box 103, Item barcode 39002038374030)
    Crouse Concert.
  - Decoration Day (9/28/73) -- Tone Roads No. 2 (1965), 1973 September 28; 1 (Box 103, Item barcode 39002038373842)
  - Gayle Ross and Douglas Brook performance, 1976 May 4; 1 (Box 103, Item barcode 39002038373859)
    Performers: Gayle Ross; Douglas Brook.
  - Songs from Recital, 1973 February 19; 1 (Box 103, Item barcode 39002038373867)
    Hamilton College Chapel.
  - Charlie Rutlage, 1976 June 2; 1977 November 18; 1 (Box 105A, Item barcode 39002038373875)
    Yale Band.
  - Symphony No. 2 (1st half), 1980 November 19; 1 (Box 105A, Item barcode 39002038373883)
  - Symphony No. 4, 1974 October 12; 1 (Box 105A, Item barcode 39002038373909)
    Performers: New York Philharmonic; Mini Festival Ives.
  - Vancouver Symphony performance, 1974 December 13; 1 (Box 105B, Item barcode 39002038373917)
    Performers: Vancouver Symphony Orchestra; Lukas Foss, conductor.
  - Symphony No. 2 (2nd half), 1980 November 19; 1 (Box 105A, Item barcode 39002038373891)
    Performers: Yale Philharmonia.
  - Ives; Popper; R. Strauss, 1971 November 14; 1 (Box 105B, Item barcode 39002038373933)
    Performers: American Symphony Orchestra; Leopold Stokowski, conductor.
  - Brahms; Bambert; Ives, undated; 1 (Box 105B, Item barcode 39002038373941)
  - Symphony No. 4; Dub from 16mm, undated; 1 (Box 105B, Item barcode 39002038374006)
  - Symphony No. 4, Part 2; Dub from 16mm film, undated; 1 (Box 105B, Item barcode 39002038374014)
  - World of Music; Dub from 16mm, undated; 1 (Box 105B, Item barcode 39002038373958)
  - Music for Good Dissonance, 1975; 1 (Box 105B, Item barcode 39002038373982)
  - Ragtime Dance No.1 (World Premiere), 1976 April 22; 1 (Box 106, Item barcode 39002038374089)
    Performers: Chamber Orchestra of New England. James Sinclair, conductor. Sprague Hall, Yale University.
  - Symphony No. 3 -- Ragtime Dance No.3 (World Premiere), 1976 April 22; 1 (Box 106, Item barcode 39002038374071)
  - Washington's Birthday, 1975 February 7; 1 (Box 105B, Item barcode 39002038373990)
    Performers: Edo de Waert, conductor.
  - 14 Lieder, 1969 January 28; 1 (Box 106, Item barcode 39002038374139)
    Performers: William Pearson, baritone; Wilhelm Nauhaus, piano.
  - Symphony No. 4, 1967 August 18; 1 (Box 106, Item barcode 39002038374105)
    Performers: Boston Symphony Orchestra; Gunther Schuller, conductor. Music Shed At Tanglewood.
  - City College Of New York, 1968 February 9; 1 (Box 106, Item barcode 39002038374121)
  - Three Places in New England; Dub, 1969 October 11; 1 (Box 106B, Item barcode 39002038374063)
    Performers: Boston Symphony Orchestra; Michael Tilson Thomas, conductor.
  - Three Places in New England; Dub, 1969 December 18; 1 (Box 105B, Item barcode 39002038374055)
  - Trio For Violoncello, Violin & Piano Forte; Dub, undated; 1 (Box 105B, Item barcode 39002038374022)
    Performers: Felix Galimir; Siegfried Palm; David Golub.
  - Central Park In The Dark, 1974 October 18; 1 (Box 105B, Item barcode 39002038373966)
    Performers: Boston Symphony Orchestra; Ozawa, conductor.
  - Symphony No. 2 -- 3 Places in New England, 1974; 1 (Box 106, Item barcode 39002038374097)
    Performers: Yale Symphony Orchestra.
  - Lawrence R. Wolf Performance, 1975 April 21; 1 (Box 106, Item barcode 39002038374113)
    Performers: Lawrence R. Wolf, piano. Sprague Memorial Hall.
  - Spoken Portions of NET program of Symphony No. 4, undated; 1 (Box 105B, Item barcode 39002038374048)
  - Dessoff Choirs Performance, 1974 March 30; 1 (Box 105B, Item barcode 39002038373974)
    Performers: Dessoff Choirs. Alice Tully Hall, Lincoln Center.
  - Messiaen; Ives; Debussy; Ravel, 1970 June 20; 1 (Box 105A, Item barcode 39002038373735)
    Performers: London Symphony Orchestra; Leopold Stokowski.
  - Symphony No.2 -- Symphony No.4 -- Three Places in New England, undated; 1 (Box 116, Item barcode 39002038373784)
    HSR Tape No. YT7-3275; YT7-3276; YT7-3277.
  - Ives Conference Concert, 1974 November 20; 1 (Box 116, Item barcode 39002038373768)
  - Ives Conference Concert, 1974 October 20; 1 (Box 115, Item barcode 39002038373750)
  - Ives Conference Concert, 1974 October 20; 1 (Box 115, Item barcode 39002038373743)
  - The Unanswered Question, undated; 1; Unlike all other materials in this collection, this item is not digitized. The tape is too brittle to be transferred. (Box 105A, Item barcode 39002038373818)
    Performers: Shaw (?).
  - Interviews; Ives Centennial Festival-Conference, 1974 October; 1 (Box 106, Item barcode 39002128474344)
    Brooklyn College.
  - Ives Centennial Conference; 2 of 2, 1974 October 21; 1 (Box 106, Item barcode 39002128474351)
    Center Church.
  - Ives Centennial Conference, 1974 October 21; 1 (Box 106, Item barcode 39002128474369)
    Center Church on the Green.
  - Ives Conference Concert, 1974 October 20; 1 (Box 116, Item barcode 39002128474393)
    Sprague Hall.
  - Ives Conference; Sound of Ives Festival; reel 2, 1974 October 20; 1 (Box 116, Item barcode 39002128474377)
  - Ives Festival, 1974 October 20; 1 (Box 116, Item barcode 39002128474401)
  - Ives festival; reel 3, 1974 October 20; 1 (Box 116, Item barcode 39002128474385)
  - Weber; Verdi; Ives, 1963 April 5; 1 (Box 110, Item barcode 39002038370517)
  - The Unanswered Question (Ives); Bach; Brahms; Beethoven, 1967 February 14; 1 (Box 110, Item barcode 39002038370525)
    Performers: New Haven Symphony Orchestra; Frank Brieff, conductor; Yoko Matsuda, violin; Ralph Kirshbaum, Cello.
  - Job 63628; Reel #1, undated; 1 (Box 110, Item barcode 39002038370533)
  - Job 63628; Reel #2, undated; 1 (Box 110, Item barcode 39002038370541)
  - Job 63628; Reel #3, undated; 1 (Box 110, Item barcode 39002038370558)
  - Job 63628; Reel #4, undated; 1 (Box 110, Item barcode 39002038370566)
  - Sonata No. 2, 1971 August 11; 1 (Box 111, Item barcode 39002038370574)
    Performers: Easley Blackwood, piano.
  - Ives; Bonus record; side 1, undated; 1 (Box 111, Item barcode 39002038370582)
  - Ives; Bonus record; side 2, undated; 1 (Box 111, Item barcode 39002038370590)
  - Hawthorne -- Thoreau, circa 1955; 1 (Box 103, Item barcode 39002038370616)
  - Mozart: Sonata in D -- Ives: Emerson -- Hawthorne, circa 1955; 1 (Box 103, Item barcode 39002038370608)
  - Reminiscences of Ives, 1974 February 12; 1 (Box 103, Item barcode 39002038370624)
    Performers: John Kirkpatrick. At Cal. St. Univ. Fullerton.
  - The Circus Band, 1974; 1 (Box 103, Item barcode 39002038370640)
    Ives Concert 1974: Grosvenor Square.
  - Reminiscences of Ives, 1974 February 12; 1 (Box 103, Item barcode 39002038370632)
  - Reminiscences about Charles Ives, 1975 March 6; 1 (Box 103, Item barcode 39002038370657)
  - Yale Reports: Charles Ives's Theater Orchestra Music, 1974 June 23; 1 (Box 103, Item barcode 39002038370665)
  - Yale Reports: Modern Music and the Debt to Charles Ives, Part One, 1970 December 27; 1 (Box 103, Item barcode 39002038370673)
  - Yale Reports: Modern Music and the Debt to Charles Ives. Part Two, 1971 January 3; 1 (Box 103, Item barcode 39002038370681)
  - Three Places in New England, 1977 July 29; 1 (Box 103A, Item barcode 39002038370699)
    Norfolk.
  - Ives; Ruggles, undated; 1 (Box 103A, Item barcode 39002038370707)
    Aaron Copland: NET Program.
  - Ives Performing, undated; 1 (Box 103A, Item barcode 39002038370731)
    Performers: Charles Ives.
  - Songs of Charles Ives, 1968 December 29; 1 (Box 103A, Item barcode 39002038370715)
  - Songs of Charles Ives, 1968 December 29; 1 (Box 103A, Item barcode 39002038370723)
  - Blake Stern Performance, 1953-1970; 1 (Box 103A, Item barcode 39002038370749)
    Performers: Blake Stern.
  - Ives' Records 1, 1924-1938; 1 (Box 103A, Item barcode 39002038370756)
  - Ives' Records 2, 1939 March 24; 1 (Box 103A, Item barcode 39002038370764)
  - Ives' Records 3, 1939 March 31; 1 (Box 103A, Item barcode 39002038370772)
  - Ives' Records 4, 1939 July 17; 1 (Box 103A, Item barcode 39002038370780)
  - Ives' Records 5, 1939 September 28; 1 (Box 103A, Item barcode 39002038370798)
  - Ives' Records 6, 1939 September 28–1941; 1 (Box 103A, Item barcode 39002038370806)
  - Ives' Records 7, 1941 November 11–1943 March 17; 1 (Box 103A, Item barcode 39002038370814)
  - Ives' Records 8, 1943 March 16–1943 March 17; 1 (Box 103A, Item barcode 39002038370822)
  - NY Town Hall acetates - 1, 1939 January 20; 1 (Box 106, Item barcode 39002128474419)
  - NY Town Hall acetates - 2, 1939 January 20; 1 (Box 106, Item barcode 39002128474427)
  - NY Town Hall acetates - 3, 1939 January 20; 1 (Box 106, Item barcode 39002128474435)
  - NY Town Hall - 1, 1939 February 24; 1 (Box 106, Item barcode 39002128474443)
  - NY Town Hall - 2, 1939 February 24; 1 (Box 106A, Item barcode 39002128474450)
  - NY Town Hall - 3, 1939 February 24; 1 (Box 106A, Item barcode 39002128474468)
  - Ives Concert: 1 of 3, 1956 February 22; 1 (Box 104, Item barcode 39002038371028)
  - Symphony No 3., 1946 September 14; 1 (Box 103B, Item barcode 39002038370962)
  - Charles E Ives: Symphony no 3: Invitation to Music, 1946 September 11; 1 (Box 103B, Item barcode 39002038370954)
  - Symphony No. 3, 1952 September 6; 1 (Box 103B, Item barcode 39002038370970)
  - Ives Concert: 2 of 3, 1956 February 22; 1 (Box 104, Item barcode 39002038371036)
  - Ives Concert: 3 of 3, 1956 February 22; 1 (Box 104, Item barcode 39002038371044)
  - Ives' concert: Reel 1, 1963 May 11; 1 (Box 104, Item barcode 39002038370996)
  - Ives' Concert: Reel 2, undated; 1 (Box 104, Item barcode 39002038371002)
  - Ives Concert: Reel 3, undated; 1 (Box 104, Item barcode 39002038371010)
  - Ives' Records 10, 1946 February 22; 1 (Box 103B, Item barcode 39002038370848)
  - Ives' Records 11, 1946 February 22; 1 (Box 103B, Item barcode 39002038370855)
  - Ives' Records 12, 1946 September 11–1948 September 13; 1 (Box 103B, Item barcode 39002038370863)
  - Ives' Records 13, 1948 September 13; 1 (Box 103B, Item barcode 39002038370871)
  - Ives' Records 14, 1951 March 4; 1 (Box 103B, Item barcode 39002038370889)
  - Ives' Records 15, undated; 1 (Box 103B, Item barcode 39002038370897)
  - Ives' Records 16, 1940 February 12; 1 (Box 103B, Item barcode 39002038370905)
  - Ives' Records 17, 1937 October 15; 1 (Box 103B, Item barcode 39002038370913)
  - Ives' Records 9, 1943 March 31; 1 (Box 103B, Item barcode 39002038370830)
  - Symphony No. 2, 1956 September 5; 1 (Box 103B, Item barcode 39002038370939)
  - Symphony No. 2, 1956 September 5; 1 (Box 103B, Item barcode 39002038370947)
  - Symphony No. 3, undated; 1 (Box 104, Item barcode 39002038370988)
  - Washington's Birthday, 1954 March 21; 1 (Box 104, Item barcode 39002038370921)
  - Charles Ives Music Examples Reel #3, undated; 1 (Box 104A, Item barcode 39002038372216)
  - Charles Ives: Musical Examples; part 1 of 3, undated; 1 (Box 104A, Item barcode 39002038372190)
  - Charles Ives: Musical Examples; part 2 of 3, undated; 1 (Box 104A, Item barcode 39002038372208)
  - Songs of Charles Ives; part 2, 1968 December 29; 1 (Box 104, Item barcode 39002038372109)
    Performers: Helen Boatwright.
  - Dorian String Quartet performance, 1939 July 29–1991 March 5; 1 (Box 104A, Item barcode 39002038372273)
  - Piano Sonata No. 1, 1969 August 31; 1 (Box 104, Item barcode 39002038372158)
    Performers: Joan Cobb, piano.
  - Dutch program on Ives, undated; 1 (Box 104A, Item barcode 39002038372224)
  - Faculty Recital program 6: Ives, 1969 February 7; 1 (Box 104A, Item barcode 39002038372240)
  - Ives Songs #1, 1968 December 29; 1 (Box 104, Item barcode 39002038372117)
  - Ives reel #60, circa 1971; 1 (Box 104, Item barcode 39002038372125)
  - Violin Sonata 2nd and 3rd movements, circa 1924; 1 (Box 104A, Item barcode 39002038372182)
  - 13 Songs, 1968 June 11; 1 (Box 104A, Item barcode 39002038372166)
  - Ives: Concert Hall C-7 Dubbing, undated; 1 (Box 104A, Item barcode 39002038372265)
  - Ives: NMQR Dubbings, undated; 1 (Box 104A, Item barcode 39002038372257)
  - Ives: Postlude in F, 1971 June 6; 1 (Box 104A, Item barcode 39002038372174)
  - Modern Music and the Debt to Charles Ives; Part 1, 1970 December 27; 1 (Box 104, Item barcode 39002038372141)
    James Drew.
  - Modern Music and the Debt to Charles Ives; Part 2, 1971 January 3; 1 (Box 104, Item barcode 39002038372133)
  - Five Songs, undated; 1 (Box 104A, Item barcode 39002038372232)
    Performers: Jean Lunn.
  - Ives: 4 Songs -- Orff: Carmina Burana, 1967-1974; 1 (Box 105, Item barcode 39002038372307)
  - Sing Out Sweet Land: Theatre Guild: Part 1, 1945 October 21–1979 April 5; 1 (Box 104A, Item barcode 39002038372281)
  - Piano Sonata No. 2, Concord Massachusetts, 1969 February 7; 1 (Box 104A, Item barcode 39002038372299)
  - Pej Takes; reel 6, undated; 1 (Box 113, Item barcode 39002038373578)
  - Symphony No. 2, 1976 January 10; 1 (Box 105, Item barcode 39002038373511)
    Performers: American Symphony Orchestral; D. Lewis, conductor.
  - Charles Ives; The 100th anniversary, undated; 1 (Box 114, Item barcode 39002038373669)
  - Piano Sonata No. 2 Concord Massachusetts 1840-1860; Charles Ives; The 100th anniversary, 1974 March 13; 1 (Box 115, Item barcode 39002038373677)
  - Crouse Concert; Syracuse University School of Music, 1969 November 2; 1 (Box 115, Item barcode 39002038373636)
  - In Search of Charles Ives, undated; 1 (Box 115, Item barcode 39002038373644)
  - Ives Centenary Concert, undated; 1 (Box 114, Item barcode 39002038373594)
    Performers: Ken Singleton.